Register to the Paul Hindemith Collection
Yale University Music Library
- ARTICLES ABOUT PAUL HINDEMITH, 1924-1988; Series VI; 1' (3 boxes)
  - ARTICLES IN ENGLISH
    - Articles in English, after 1964 (Box 17, Folder 301)
      - R. G. Pauly: Concert to Honor Composer, in The Oregonian (Portland), 15 November 1970
      - A. Main: Hindemith Tomorrow, an address delivered at Ohio State University, 8 Dec 1973
      - A. Main: Hindemith and Three Painters, in The Arts, Ohio State University, 1974
      - W. Hilse: review of G. Skelton's Paul Hindemith: The Man Behind the Music, in Music Library Association Notes, Sept 1978
      - H. M. Blumenfeld: Ad Vocem Adorno, 1982
      - B. Lundegaard: Hindemith Directed [George Roy] Hill from Music to Words, article in Minneapolis newspaper Oct; also review by Lundegaard of Hill's film "The Little Drummer Girl", 1984
    - Articles in English, after 1964, cont. (Box 17, Folder 302)
      - H. Boatwright: Paul Hindemith as a Teacher, in The Musical Quarterly July, with related correspondence, 1964
      - G. Lam: Paul Hindemith (1895-1963), in the Yearbook of the American Philosophical Society Vol. VII, No. 3, 1965
      - L. Klein: Paul Hindemith. His Rise and Fall, in Music Educators Journal May - a part of 20th Century Analysis, Essays in Miniature, 1967
      - G. George: ...Opprobria fingere saevus, unpublished rebuttal of H. Redlich's attack in Music Review, sent to Collection in 1973, 1964
      - E. Krenek: Comments made to Vivian Perlis for Yale Oral History Project, 1977
      - D. Hurwitz: The Dilemma of a German Composer. Paul Hindemith's Changing Style, Philosophy, and Fortune - unpublished master's thesis, 1983
      - M. Vernazza: Paul Hindemith - Music Educator, in American Music Teacher, June/July 1984
      - R. Hills: Hindemith and Auden. As Regards the Avant Garde, in The Quarterly, pub. by Yale Daily News, Fall 1984
      - E. Richter: Training Prospective Composers to be Compleat Musicians. Hindemith's Teaching at the Berlin Hochschule, in Gamut, Journal of the Georgia Association of Music Theorists Vol. 2, 1985
      - D. Neumeyer: Paul Hindemith. A New Assessment, in Keynote, pub. by WNCN New York, Dec 1985
  - HINDEMITH JAHRBUCH ARTICLES
    All translations in English are the work of Luther Noss.
    - JAHRBUCH I, translations only, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 303)
      - Helmut Haack(?): Foreword
      - Helmut Haack(?): The Establishment of the Hindemith Foundation
      - L. Finscher: Paul Hindemith - Search for a New Orientation
      - A. Briner: Hindemith and Adorno's Critique of Music Makers
      - A. Zabrsa: Hindemith's Opera Projects
    - JAHRBUCH II, translations only, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 304)
      - D. Rexroth: Introduction - literal translation unrevised in longhand
      - W. Kirsch: The Late Hindemith - introduction only in longhand; comments on the Mass, Long Christmas Dinner, Organ Concerto are filed in individual composition folders
      - K. Laux: Scandal in Baden-Baden
      - D. Rexroth: Early Hindemith. Tradition and Reflection - introduction only; major portion filed with Second String Quartet, opus 16
    - JAHRBUCH III, translations only, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 304)
      - H. Curjel: Recollections of Hindemith
      - D. Rexroth: The Moral Responsibility of the Artist. Hindemith's Operas
    - JAHRBUCH IV, translations only, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 305)
      - R. Stephan: On Paul Hindemith
      - H. Stuckenschmidt: Hindemith's Breakout and Homecoming, address at the opening of the Hindemith Institute in Frankfurt, 7 Sept 1974
      - A. Briner: Paul Hindemith and Arnold Schönberg
      - K. von Maur: Oskar Schlemmer and Paul Hindemith
      - S. Borris: Perspectives on Hindemith's Involvement with the Morality of Art
      - W. E. Rebner: My Teacher Hindemith
      - H. Kayser: Letter to Paul Hindemith, 20 Feb 1936
    - JAHRBUCH V, translations only, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 305)
      - P. Cahn: review of G. Skelton: Paul Hindemith. The Man Behind the Music
      - J. Breuer: The First Bartok Recording. Quartet No. 2, opus 17 by Amar-Hindemith Quartet
      - P. Cahn: Paul Hindemith in Frankfurt
      - P. Mohler: Paul Hindemith, an Address upon Paul Hindemith's 80th Birthday
    - JAHRBUCH VI, translations only, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 306)
      - B. Billeter: Hindemith's Development as a Composer as Reflected in his Piano Works
      - D. Rexroth: Hindemith's Chamber Music
    - JAHRBUCH VII, translations only, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 306)
      - G. Schubert: The Complete Edition of Hindemith's Work
      - R. Stephan: Adorno and Hindemith. Toward an Understanding of a Difficult Relationship
    - JAHRBUCH VIII, translations only, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 306)
      - A. Greither: Paul Hindemith and Ladislav Cerny
    - JAHRBUCH XI, translations only, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 306)
      - N. Schneider: Hindemith's Reception in Germany, 1945-1955
    - JAHRBUCH XV, translations only, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 306)
      - C. M. Altar: My Meetings with Paul Hindemith in Ankara in 1935
      - C. Zimmerman-Kalyoncu: Paul Hindemith in Turkey
      - E. Rexroth: Hindemith's Contribution to Turkey's Musical Life
  - FOREIGN ARTICLES
    The articles from foreign sources are all translated into English by Luther Noss, except where indicated.
    - Foreign Articles, before 1940 (Box 17, Folder 307)
      - A. Weissmann: Paul Hindemith, in Die Musik XVI; with photocopy of original, 8 May 1924
      - P. Bekker: Paul Hindemith, in Musikblätter des Anbruch Vol. 7; with photocopy of original, 1925
      - T. Adorno: Chamber Music of Paul Hindemith, in Die Musik XIX; original only, 1 Oct 1926
      - E. Bennighoven: The Spirit in Hindemith's Work [in longhand], in Die Musik XXI; with photocopy of original, 10 July 1929
      - K. Wesphal: Paul Hindemith, in Schweizerische Musikzeitung XX, 1930
      - B. Stürmer: An Open Letter to Professor Paul Hindemith, in Die Musik XXIII; with photocopy of original, 1 Oct 1930
      - P. Epstein: Paul Hindemiths Theatermusik, in Die Musik XXIII; original only, translation filed with Neues vom Tage, 8 May 1931
      - F. Welter: Paul Hindemith. Culturally and Politically Intolerable, in Die Musik XXIV; with photocopy of original, 2 Nov 1934
      - H. Gerigk: The Foreign Press and German Music, in Die Musik XXVII; with photocopy of original, 4 Jan 1935
      - A. Rosenberg: Aesthetics - or the People's struggle in Die Musik XXVII; with 4 photocopies of original, 4 Jan 1935
      - F. Herzog: The Hindemith-Furtwängler case, in Die Musik XXVII; with photocopy of original, 4 Jan 1935
      - P. Goebbels: Excerpt from address to Cultural Council in Berlin 6 Dec 1934 after Furtwängler was fired, in Die Musik XXVII; with photocopy of original, 4 Jan 1935
      - E. Krenek: passages from Neue Musik; no copy of original, 1937
    - Foreign Articles, 1946-1960 (Box 18, Folder 308)
      - O.-E. Schilling: Paul Hindemith, a study, from Der Standpunkt Vol. 3 (Stuttgart); with original, 1946
      - H. Mersmann: Paul Hindemith, in Neue Musikzeitschrift May (Munich); with original, 1947
      - B. Geissmar: The Hindemith Case, in Musica 2; with photocopy of original, 1948
      - Diskussion mit Hindemith, incomplete clipping from Munich newspaper, 1949
      - M. Labroca: Hindemith dirige all'Auditorium di Torino, clipping from Italian musical periodical [see also reverse side], late 1940s
      - H. Hackenbroich: Musicians of Today. Fulda, chapter on Hindemith; no original, 1949
      - Hindemith dirigerer ny symfoni, in Programbladet. Oslo, in Norwegian; no translation, 24 Feb 1952
      - E. Preussner: History of Western Music. Vienna, section on Hindemith; no original, 1951
      - Liko [Licco] Anar: My Friendship with Paul Hindemith, in Melos 22; with photocopy of original, 1953
      - L. Schrade: Hindemith in the New World, a 60th birthday commemorative, in Melos 22 with photocopy of original, 1955
      - R. Schollum: Metamorphoses on the Theme Hindemith, in Musica, commemorating Paul Hindemith 60th birthday; with photocopy of original, Nov 1955
      - H. Strobel: Zeugnis in Bildern, introduction; no original, 1955
      - E. Krenek: American influence on Immigrant Composers, in Musica 13; with photocopy of original, 1959
    - Foreign Articles, 1960-1969 (Box 18, Folder 309)
      - P. Mohler: Introduction to program of Staatliche Hochschule & Hoch Conservatory Festival in Frankfurt; with original, 2-8 May 1960
      - G. Marbach: Oskar Schlemmer's Associations with Scherchen, Schönberg, and Hindemith, in Neue Zeitschrift für Musik Vol. 12 - translation only of references to Paul Hindemith with partial photocopy of original, 1962
      - J. Wulf: Musik im dritten Reich, references to Paul Hindemith; no original, 1963
      - H. Strobel: German Music between two World Wars, in Melos; with photocopy of original, 2-8 May 1963
      - K. Schumann: comments for Heliodor recording of The Four Temperaments and Symphonic Dances (written after 1963), 1960
      - H. Mersmann: Paul Hindemith, a German Musician, an address, in Kontrapunkte 7; no original, 1964
      - J. Häusler: The Classicist Paul Hindemith, in Melos; with photocopy of original, Jan 1964
      - A strange tribute on Frankfurt Radio by T. A. Adorno commemorating Hindemith's 68th birthday after his death, in Schott-Kurier; + original, 15 Dec 1964
      - W. Schuh: Paul Hindemith: Die letzten Jahre, introduction; no original, 1965
      - K. Ruppel: Paul Hindemith. An Influential Life or a Portrait and Monument, in Melos; with photocopy of original, Nov 1965
      - A. Briner: Hindemith and Progress in the 20th Century, in Melos; with photocopy of original, Aug 1966
      - E. Jacobi: Paul Hindemith as a Teacher, in Schweitzer Monatshefte 45; with original, 11 Feb 1966
      - 70th Birthday commemorative edition of Schott-Kurier: In memoriam Paul Hindemith, 5 Jan 1966
      - A. Rubeli: Paul Hindemith in the Early 1920s, address presented at ISM Ljubljana, 1967
      - W. Pütz: Hindemith's String Quartets, excerpts, 1968
      - T. W. Adorno: Ad vocem Hindemith, in Impromptus Suhrkamp/Frankfurt, a collection of articles, 1922-1962
    - Foreign Articles, 1970-1976 (Box 18, Folder 310)
      - in Frankfurt City Library booklet, 1970
      - H. Weshaupt: Hindemith's Educational Music
      - G. Koch: Hindemith's Theater Music
      - G. Schroth: Hindemith's Piano Music
      - H. Rösner: Hindemith's Orchestral Music
      - H. Zietsch: Hindemith's Chamber Music
      - H. Vogt: references in Neue Musik seit 1945, 1972
      - A. Rubeli: Hindemiths a cappella Werke, Introduction and Foreword, 1973
      - Revue Musicale de Suisse Romande - Numéro spécial Paul Hindemith June, no translations, 1973
      - H. Weber: Hindemith Workshop in Bonn, in Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung; no translation, 27 Mar 1975
      - H. Weber: Report on L'Ecole Hindemith in Blonay summer, in Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung, 1975
      - D. Rexroth, ed.: Am Beispiel Paul Hindemith. Musik und Kunst der Zwanziger, Workshop in Bonn; no translations, 20-23 Mar 1975
      - D. Brennecke: Paul Hindemith, the Antipode of Schönberg, in untitled East German musicological periodical commemorating 25th anniversary of Schönberg's death; with photocopy of original, 1976
    - Foreign Articles, 1977-1988 (Box 18, Folder 311)
      - G. Schubert: Concerning some of Hindemith's late works, in Melos, Feb 1977
      - D. Rexroth: article in Berlin Festival program, 1977
      - Berliner Festwochen - program, 2 Sept-8 Oct 1977
      - Schlemmer's "Triadic Ballet" in Berlin
      - B. Billeter: Introduction to V, 10 Piano Music, 1979
      - in Hindemith Cycle - Nordrhein Westphal program 1980-81
      - - D. Rexroth: The Young Hindemith
      - - G. Schubert: Hindemith's Later Development
      - G. Schubert: Hindemiths Bearbeitungen eigener und fremder Werke - Ein Überblick, in Schweizer Jahrbuch für Musikwissenschaft no. 3 untranslated, 1983
      - Hindemith-Tage Munich program untranslated, 16-19 February 1984
      - A. Briner-D. Rexroth-D. Schubert: Paul Hindemith, a pictorial biography - translation by L. Noss, 1988
  - INTERVIEWS
    - Interviews from Newspapers and Periodicals (Box 18, Folder 312)
      - G. Lieberson: Hindemith on Teaching Composition, in Musical America, 25 Apr 1939
      - A. Berger: Hindemith Returns from Germany, in New York Herald Tribune, 10 Apr 1949
      - H. Gleason: Faculty Profile - Paul Hindemith, in Harvard Crimson, 29 Nov 1949
      - W. Stresemann: Paul Hindemith's Impressions of German Musical Life, in Sonntagsblatt Staat-Zeitung und Herold New York; + photocopy of original in German, 10 Apr 1949
      - Anon.: Music in Germany is Seen on Decline, in New York Times, which brought heavy criticism from German press. See Briner's biography for the "explanation" Paul Hindemith had to write, 31 Mar 1949
      - R. Shaw: Music Is Order, excerpt in American Music Teacher, Sept-Oct 1949
      - J. Harrison in New York Herald Tribune, 15 & 22 Feb 1959
      - a) Paul Hindemith - His Art and his Views
      - b) More on Hindemith - a "Free" Composer
      - E. Salzman: Paul Hindemith, Master of Many Trades, in New York Times, 15 Feb 1959
      - H. Taubman: A Pampered Age?, in New York Herald Tribune, 20 Mar 1960
  - NEWSPAPER ARTICLES
    - Newspaper Stories and Articles, 1937-1983 (Box 18, Folder 313)
      - Composers' League Honors Hindemith, in New York Times - typescript, 19 Apr 1937
      - Chicago Cuts a Cake, in Time magazine photocopy, 24 Dec 1945
      - Hindemith's Big Week, in Time magazine, 23 Feb 1948
      - Hindemith at Home in Frankfurt, in The Stars and Stripes, Frankfurt, 12 Feb 1949
      - Hindemith vor Musikstudenten, in Berlin Telegraf + original, 19 Apr 1949
      - E. Mahlke: Anstrengender Besuch - open letter in Sozialdemokrat Berlin + original, 19 Feb 1949
      - Das Hanauer Frühjahrsereignis - untranslated article in typescript, Feb? 1952
      - Während Orpheus, in Dusseldorf newspaper, 15? Mar 1952
      - Pittsburgh International Contemporary Music Festival - press release showing interest in contemporary composers, 8 June 1952
      - Hindemith - en forkjemper for kunstens og menneskets frihet, in Oslo Dagblatt, untranslated, 24? Feb 1952
      - Priset ger Hindemith skapartid, in Stockholm newspaper? untranslated, Winter? Feb 1952
      - Hindemith Will Vacate Faculty Post, in Yale Daily News, 28 Apr 1953
      - Sibelius Prize Award, in New Haven Register 25 Apr, New Haven Journal Courier 10 Oct + one more unidentified, 1955
      - Hindemith legt Veto ein, in Die Abendzeitung Munich - brief translation + original, 23 Dec 1953
      - Ein Bildnis von Paul Hindemith - Gabe für die Musikhochschule, in Frankfurter Neue Presse; original without translation, 23 Dec 1958
      - 7 Guests Named by Philharmonic, in New York Times, 31 Mar 1959
      - Hindemith i Filharmoniske, in Oslo newspaper, 17? Sept 1959
      - Berlin Philharmonic concert announcement, 1 Oct 1960
      - The Compleat Musician, in Time magazine - typescript, 18 Oct 1960
      - P. Hume: Hindemith Provides a Double Delight, in Washington Post (Star?), 18 Mar 1963
      - J. White: Hindemith Coming Here Sunday to Conduct own Opera, Ballet, in Washington Star (Post?), 18 Mar 1963
      - Yale Alumni Magazine, Dec - complete copy; see Folder 301 for contents and another copy, 1964
      - "Hindemith Month" in Many Nations, in The Bulletin issued by the Press & Information Office of the German Federal Government in Bonn, 23 Nov 1965
      - D. O. White: Paul Hindemith. A Composer's Response to Political Repression - a lecture at Amherst College; announcement only, 14 Mar 1978
      - Repertoire list for the 1979 Deutscher Musikwettbewerb
      - Announcement of summer course in "Hindemithian Theory and Practice"
      - M. Landsberger: Footnote to Buffalo Musical Life Involves Composer Hindemith, in Buffalo News - photocopy, 6 Apr 1980
      - N. Robertson: Slatkin Conducts the Moderns, in New York Times, 28 Jan 1983
  - REVIEWS
    - Reviews of Concerts, Books, Recordings, 1937-1983 (Box 18, Folder 314)
      (for reviews of individual compositions, see separate folders for same)
      - O. Downes: Hindemith Works Heard in Capital, in New York Times, 11 Apr 1937
      - G. Gilbert: New York Times review of Town Hall concert, with notes from Paul Hindemith Journal to Gertrud Hindemith, 24 Apr 1939
      - H. Auchincloss Jr: Hindemith Presents "Bible Sonatas" of Biber, in Yale Daily News, 24 Feb 1942
      - Paul Hindemith - Performing Musician, a circular of European press comments on performances prepared by Associated Music Publishers, 1947
      - Internationale Musikalische Festwochen 1947-4. Symphoniekonzert, in Luzerner Neueste Nachrichten - without translation, 25 Aug 1947
      - H. Taubman: Records- Hindemith, in New York Times, 30 Jan 1949
      - F. Brust: Mit Pathos der Sachlichkeit - Hindemith dirigierte in München, in a Munich newspaper, 6 Feb 1949
      - K. Reinhard: High Point of the Concert Season, in unknown Berlin newspaper; + original, Feb 1949
      - E. Kroll: Plastische Melodienbildung - Die Philharmoniker unter Paul Hindemith, in unknown newspaper, Feb 1949
      - K. Reinhard: Hindemith dirigiert eigene Werke, in unknown newspaper, Feb 1949
      - W. Panofsky: Hindemith dirigiert Hindemith, in Münchener Süddeutsche Zeitung, 4 July 1955
      - P. Cater: This fine concert showed a genius as TWO men, in Scottish Daily Mail, 25 Aug 1955
      - Reviews of concerts in Japan of Vienna Philharmonic under Paul Hindemith, Apr 1956
      - J. Harrison: Two interviews in New York Herald Tribune; (see Folder 312), 15 Feb-22 Feb 1959
      - H. Taubman: Hindemith Leads Premieres of 2 Works at Town Hall, in New York Times, 16 Feb 1959
      - L. Biancolli: Paul Hindemith at Town Hall, in New York World Telegram and Sun, 16 Feb 1959
      - P. H. Lang: Hindemith Concert, in New York Herald Tribune, 16 Feb 1959
      - M. Kastendieck: Hoorah for Hindemith, in New York Journal American, 16 Feb 1959
      - H. Johnson: Hindemith Returns after Five Years, in New York Post, 16 Feb 1959
      - E. Salzman: Paul Hindemith, Master of Many Trades, in New York Times, 15 Feb 1959
      - M. C.: review in Musical Courier, Mar 1959
      - H. Taubman: Paul Hindemith Leads the Philharmonic, in New York Times ?, 1960
      - Three Composers Cited by Critics, in New York Times, 18 Feb 1960
      - E. Helm: Hindemith Opens New Concert Hall in Cultural Trossinger, in San Francisco Sunday Chronicle, 15 Jan 1961
      - Reviews of Chicago Symphony concerts, 1961
      - R. Dettmer: Hindemith, 66, Thrills Ravinia, in Chicago's American, 26 July 1961
      - R. C. Marsh: A Rewarding Ravinia Night by Hindemith, in Chicago Sun-Times, 26 July 1961
      - R. Dettmer: Hindemith Scores Again, in Chicago's American, 28 July 1961
      - R. C. Marsh: Hindemith's Performance Memorable, in Chicago Sun-Times, 28 July 1961
      - D. Henahan: Paul Hindemith Leads a Superior Schubert, in Chicago Daily News, 28 July 1961
      - R. C. Marsh: Hindemith Triumph Worth Shouting About, in Chicago Sun-Times, 31 July 1961
      - H. C. Schonberg: Hindemith Leads Philharmonic in his Requiem, in New York Times, 20 Apr 1963
      - W. Hilse: review of Hindemith Anthology; 3-record set of selected chamber works GSC 1-3, in The Musical Quarterly, Oct 1973
      - R. Ericson: Complete Sonatas for Brass & Piano, Glenn Gould and Philadelphia Brass Ensemble Columbia M2-33971, in New York Times, 26 June 1976
      - A. Chipman: Composers Conduct - review of Requiem recording on Odyssey (Col, Y-33821) conducted by Paul Hindemith, also Sonatas for Brass and Piano (Col M2-33971) with G. Gould et al, in New Haven Register, 5 Sept 1976
      - R. Close: Concert a Boost for Hindemith, in Minneapolis Star, 9 May 1977
      - P. G. Davis: Hindemith on Disks-New Light on a Prolific Composer - review of Vol. 1-2-4-6 of GSC/Consortium Recordings, in New York Times
      - K. Botsford: review of Skelton's biography, in New York Times Book Review, 27 Nov 1977
      - W. Crutchfield: Hindemith - The Viola Legacy, in New York Times, 14 Jan 1985
      - M. Taylor: Unpublished Hindemith Sonatas Recorded-review of 7 viola sonatas by Kim Kashkashian for ECM and H. Blomstedt leading San Francisco Symphony in Mathis Symphony, Weber Metamorphosis, and Trauermusik for London Records, in New Haven Register, 11 Sept 1988
  - TYPED EXCERPTS OF ARTICLES
    - Typed excerpts of articles in New York Times, 1924-1964 (Box 18.1, Folder 315)
      Compiler of part I, to 24 Nov 1945 is unidentified; Martin Kluger compiled part II, 1945 to end.; [Notes in longhand indicate similar survey begun for Christian Science Monitor and Chicago Daily Tribune, compiler unknown].
  - OBITUARIES AND MEMORIAL PROGRAMS
    - Obituaries (Box 18.1, Folder 316)
      - New Haven Register, 30 Dec 1963
      - New York Times; front page article, H. Schonberg article, editorial, 30 Dec 1963
      - New York Herald Tribune; A. Rich's editorial, J. Molleson's article, 30 Dec 1963
      - The Boston Herald, 30 Dec 1963
      - Washington Post; UPI story, S. Rosenfeld's obituary article, 30 Dec 1963
      - New York Times Western edition; front page article and editorial, 30 Dec 1963
      - San Francisco Chronicle; AP & UP article, A. Frankenstein's editorial, front page (?) photo and brief notice, 30 Dec 1963
      - Seattle Times; page 2 AP wirephoto and brief notice, 30 Dec 1963
      - Seattle Post-Intelligence; 2 column article and photo, 30 Dec 1963
    - Obituaries (Box 18.1, Folder 317)
      - H. Strobel: Master of his Epoch, in Melos, Jan 1964
      - L. Strecker: Tribute to Paul Hindemith, in Melos; untranslated, Jan 1964
      - W. Stresemann: Eulogy delivered at burial service, 4 Jan 1964
      - H. Straumann: Eulogy read at burial service, 4 Jan 1964
      - H. Schonberg: Paul Hindemith, in New York Times, 5 Jan 1964
      - O. Daniel: 1895-Hindemith-1963, in Musical America, Jan 1964
      - Yale Daily News obituary, Jan 6 1964
      - The Bulletin issued by Press & Information Office of the German Federal Government - obituary, 7 Jan 1964
      - Time magazine - obituary, 10 Jan 1964
      - B. Boretz: obituary in The Nation, 27 Jan 1964
      - O. Brodde: closing statement of obituary article, 1964
      - Card sent by Gertrud Hindemith in acknowledgment of expression of sympathy, 16 Apr 1964
      - Letter Gertrud Hindemith-O. Noss describing details of Paul Hindemith's death (see letter file), 20 Apr 1964
      - K. Jaffee: comments on Paul Hindemith from Columbia recording of Lilacs Requiem, 1964
      - Szymon Goldberg obituary in New York Times, 20 July 1993
    - Memorial Programs (Box 18.1, Folder 317)
      - Österreichische Musikzeitschrift No. 5/6, Wiener Festwochen, 1964
      - New Haven Symphony under F. Brieff, 14 Jan 1964
      - Cappella Cordina under A. Planchart, 23 Feb 1964
      - CBS broadcast with L. Bernstein, 23 Feb 1964
      - Dartmouth College, 19 May 1964
      - Alberta College (Violet Archer), 16-23-30 May, 6-30 June 1964
    - Irwin Jacobi correspondence re: Hindemithiana collection, 1964-1975 (Box 18.1, Folder 318)
- BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS, 1916-1980; Series VII; 1' (2 boxes)
  Gathered here are numerous items collected by Luther Noss which contribute to the biography of Paul Hindemith. Personal Recollections comprise a set of articles, letters, interviews, and reminiscences. Folder 324 contains biographical information gleaned from orchestral programs, booklets, magazine articles, standard musical encyclopedias, and personal comments from friends, colleagues, and former students.
  Folder 326 contains the earliest letters from Paul Hindemith (1916-1922) covering his period of service in the German army. A list of holograph manuscripts and letters found at the Library of Congress is contained in Folder 330.